

# Rhea Labayo

## Software Engineer III

Enthusiastic and hard-working Full Stack Web Developer with over ten years of experience in creating solutions for companies' website needs across various industries. Seeking a position where I can apply my expertise in building webbased applications and websites. Eager to improve and acquire knowledge of new web technologies to work more efficiently and provide the best services to the organization.

## rhea.labayo08@gmail.com

- +639 06 0065219
- 💡 San Miguel, Bulacan
- https://rhealabayo.site
- in/rhealabayo
- /rlabayo

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Software Engineer III**

Pointwest Innovations Corporation

2019-08 - Present

Quezon City

- Attend client meetings to gather and define input and output requirements for projects.
- Discuss and create the project development timeline with the client.
- Develop and maintain an interactive and dynamic mobile-responsive website, including optimized pages for a better performance loading.
- Develop a custom Content Management System (CMS) for the website.
- Analyze, design, and develop web APIs that will be used by the frontend website.
- Integrate the Google Maps API into the website for cash-in and cash-out services through an interactive map interface.
- Report the development status to the client.
- Test, debug, and fix the errors on the website before deploying it to the test or UAT environment.
- Create reusable functions based on the given requirements.
- Create the deployment guides and deployment files for production deployment.
- Assist the client with production deployment.
- Deploy other project from local to production using GoDaddy cPanel.
- Conduct research to identify and learn about new technologies, methodologies, and techniques relevant to the upcoming project offerings.
- Create, modify, and evaluate dialogue prompts for advanced software development concepts, such as JavaScript and ReactJS, ensuring that the code snippets and test cases are functional in relation to Large Language Models (LLMs) to enhance communication and efficiency.

**Technologies used:** Codelgniter Framework, PHP, RESTful APIs, MySql, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Google Maps API, React JS, Visual Studio Code, HeidiSQL, WinSCP, Postman, Chrome Dev Tools, GoDaddy, Laravel, Jest

**Key Projects:** Collaborate with the client team to develop and maintain websites. The sites' key features include a branch locator, loan application, account application, card replacement application, inquiries, payments, FAQs, services, and other marketing-related offerings.

## Applications Engineer Rendition Digital Inc May 2017 - March 2019

Makati

• Created comprehensive workflow documentation based on the provided image forms to support application development and maintenance.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- ☑ PHP
- CodeIgniter
- RESTful APIs
- ☑ MySql
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ CSS
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- ☑ JSON
- ✓ AIAX
- Bootstrap
- ☑ Google Maps API
- TailwindCSS
- React IS
- GoDaddy
- Bluehost
- Hostinger
- ✓ Vitro API
- HeidiSQL
- ☑ WinSCP
- ☑ Visual Studio Code
- Chrome Dev Tools
- ✓ Laravel (practical knowledge)
- PHPUnit (practical knowledge)
- ☑ Github (practical knowledge)
- Jest (practical knowledge)

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Teamwork
- Attention to detail
- Stress management
- Handling criticism
- Critical thinking
- Time management
- Adaptability
- ✓ Verbal and written communication

- Collaborated with clients to understand application workflows and ensure effective communication throughout the development process.
- Developed form application based on the application workflow documentation.
- Proposed and implemented technical solutions to address issues encountered in applications, ensuring seamless functionality.
- Updated the technical documentation, including the encountered issues and its solutions.
- Reported development status or progress to the superiors and the client.
- Performed peer code reviews based on the application workflow documentation and returned the results of the review to the application owner.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Vitro API, Visual Studio Code

**Key Projects:** Worked with a team to develop web application pages for medical forms, designed to simplify the process of collecting and managing patient information.

## Web Developer

**Future IT Services** 

April 2015 - February 2017

**Pasig** 

- Attended client meetings to gather input and output requirements.
- Contributed to the development of the frontend and backend of the web-based application.
- Tested, debugged, and fixed errors in the web-based application before deploying it to the test environment.
- Reported development status or progress to the Senior Developer.
- Ensured the proper operation of the web-based application.
- Supported the needs of the clients and the users of the web-based application.

**Technologies used:** Codelgniter Framework, PHP, MySql, RESTful APIs, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Visual Studio Code, HeidiSql, Chrome Dev Tools, Postman.

**Key Projects:** Collaborated with a team to develop a project tracking system for the company to track projects, tasks, roles, employees, and time records, as well as to generate reports.

## Web Developer

Asiatype Incorporated

July 2014 - April 2015

San Juan

- Attended meetings to gather input and output requirements.
- Contributed to the development of frontend and backend of the web-based application.
- Tested, debugged, and fixed the errors in the web-based application before deploying it to the test environment.
- Reported development status or progress to the Senior Developer.
- Ensured the proper operation of the web-based application.
- Supported the needs of the users of the web-based application.

**Technologies used:** Codelgniter Framework, PHP, MySql, RESTful APIs, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Visual Studio Code, HeidiSql, Chrome Dev Tools, Postman.

**Key Projects:** Collaborated with a team to develop a project tracking system for the company to track projects, tasks, roles, employees, and time records, as well as to generate reports.

### Web Developer

**Business Profiles Inc** 

August 2012 - July 2014

Makati

- Attended meetings to gather input and output requirements.
- Developed the frontend and backend of the websites.
- Developed the Content Management System (CMS) website.
- Integrated Google Maps into the website to pin news or incidents for easier access by clients or readers to the locations of the incidents.
- Tested, debugged, and fixed the errors in the websites before deploying it to the test environment.
- Deployed the codes from test environment to production in BlueHost cPanel.
- Ensured and maintained the proper operation of the websites.
- Supported the needs of the users or researchers in using the websites.

**Technologies used:** PHP, MySql, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Google Maps API, Visual Studio Code, Bluehost

**Key Projects:** Worked with a team to develop websites and their CMS. These websites provide incident information and relevant topics for partners and readers.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** 

Polytechnic University of the Philippines

May 2012